Once you download and this page, I mean,
you can configure,
you have to configure the session.
Okay,
can you show us the IP and the port for
prod, for test, for QA? I mean,
what and all you use, I do not know.
Can you show us that?
Only, only one for one.
One Foot only.
and one IP.
which is displayed on the screen.
That is the one, right?
Yes, only.
Yes, yes.
Just, you just,
you just go to options and then connect.
Settings.
Connection.
This end.com.
What is the CISB?
Tisdi Ulwar.
Since we,
I told right there are two system and
system two who are there,
one for the DB2 usage and one for the or
Changeman.
change even except those remaining
everything is same.
Okay.
OK, can you click on?
You can create the member, say he.
Right, right.
Can you click on the edit for any one of
them? Yeah, report number 22732. OK,
can you go to the other one?
I will get a screenshot.
That's okay. It is getting recorded.
It's okay, buddy.
We don't want you to unnecessarily do
that.
OK, so this is 22732. OK, good, good. OK,
fine.
You can connect.
So once you connect that one,
then it will come through here. Here,
Mhm.
either you can log in with the SW02 or
SW05.
What will OK?
What's the difference?
Okay.
There is no difference.
Both are the same only. Whenever, I mean,
connection got stuck and suppose without
coming out,
you went outside after app number,
the user ID got logged in,
you are not able to log in.
Then you can use the second one.
Okay.
Suppose I logged in with SW02,
I did some work, then I went outside.
There is a power cut.
So after half an hour or two hours,
I came back,
then my session SW02 got logged.
That time I can log in with the SW05.
Where I got a stop, ohh,
that that test screen,
it will it it it directly it goes to the
TEST screen.
So one question, Anatha,
any chances you logged in through SW05
and then let's say, like you said,
the power went off,
you came back SW02 and then something
else happened with the regions,
both the alpha are now logged.
Have you faced encountering?
Yeah, you have to wait, I think,
20 to 30 minutes. Both will get unlocked.
Okay.
Once you log in,
it will display like this,
then you have to press F2.
Then it will display as 0205 both have
the same thing.
There is no difference for both.
All options are there in a 02 CCN is
there, and same Ms. Prod Ms.
Zero Prod is there, everything is same.
And I told N and B,
what is the difference?
It is a change man and this is a DB2.
Got it.
Hello, table one.
Here we can run system jobs also.
You can run the jobs in the system
environment and both simultaneously you
can log in in both terms.
Suppose 3.
Now I opened the two sessions, N&B.
If I want to switch
Can Windows Shift F1?
Here you can see, this is BM.
CJ.
So,
Windows Shift F12 to switch between SysB
and SysM. OK.
If...
So,
here I told right whenever there is a
amit.
Dollar. We'll start from here. Dollar.
This is say once.
All the job which are ran almost one year
backup is available.
For the job Locker.
I know, coming.
And, for,
and you gave Jane for the recent ones,
and I believe my past experience for the
other other the ones we need to give A.H.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, JN Means.
Yeah, yes, we use it in a Reeder, right?
Fame.
Okay.
Yeah, all right, right, right. Jr.
Suppose 100.
100 days data appear.
Ohh.
Yeah,
it's been a long time I've seen this
If I want a specific date.
screen.
Okay.
Yeah, suppose if you want a specific date,
then you have to give the selection data.
Mhm.
Mmh.
OK, this is.
and you know it how to retrieve from old
one to H suppose H minus 100.
Is this the recall function? Restore part?
Ohh, okay, got it, got it, yeah.
Yeah, I did.
Yes, recall function, yeah.
Just give R and hit enter, right?
If I view R.
Yeah, thanks.
Yeah, then F3.
Then, F3.
Then, submit the job, right? Yeah,
got it now.
Here, it will submit the job.
Locker, yeah.
These options,
you have to set up whenever you go,
you have to set up these options.
Center, connect me.
Thanks.
This is 1 frequently we use it,
then after that, yep.
If you go here,
here we can see all the tools,
I mean file manager, file manager,
Devu to file.
DB to manage, DB to utilities,
and Changeman. What are the tools,
main term tools are there? Here we,
from here we can access. So,
suppose it's Changeman. Currently I'm in,
so I can access the Changeman from here.
So, every time,
whenever you want to access,
you have to come
Yep, then then you have to select it.
Now I gave the name change man as a CJ
from here if I give.
It will go to the changement package.
Then, here, build the build the package.
Sorry to interrupt. Sidharth,
are you familiar with Changeman?
Have you used it recently?
Recently, no, long back.
Yeah, uh, so for me, right, Anatha,
I used change, and they were both of them,
but it is not recent,
so is there any document which we can
Mm.
follow?
No, no, no document. I mean,
once you get the access, right, I will,
that time I will explain more in detail.
Also, reverse KT, I mean,
Okay.
if you are creating the package,
then I will guide you.
Awesome, awesome,
because I don't have it on top of my mind
because it's been, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I know. I understood.
Initially, one or two packages,
whenever you are creating,
I will guide you.
Yeah, yeah,
just we just need that help and after
that we can get it going.
We just need to be spoon fed for one to
two packages.
Yes, no problem. So, once it come here,
create the package,
then check out the elements, then go to...
Once you check out the elements,
it will come to here.
This is the package I mean you created
that package name you have to give here.
All the packages starts with the ACLAPD.
So, this is already my package,
existing package, so I...
Yeah.
To open that package, you have to come,
yeah.
Hello.
And what is it? 039?
Is it date or what is that?
No, no, no, it is a number package number.
Okay.
There is no specific format.
This is just a number, random number.
If I create one,
then it allocate this one. Immediately,
Okay.
if you are creating another one, then 64.
If somebody is creating 65.
It is auto-allocated.
One way, yeah, we can see.
Allah.
Packages.
It is executive.
Coming here, you can see all the packages.
So, which I am showing you here, this one.
And after this,
this menu got created with this number.
If you are creating one more,
then it will create the 76.
Dutt.
The next one.
And here,
the this this package implementing for
this for this metric.
There is a Jayaraja ID, I believe.
Yeah, this is a zero. Mitch, I mean,
Mitch is nothing but Jayaraja.
Oprah.
Here we call Mitch. Actually,
it is a zero card.
Here we can see the creator who created
this one. This is my head.
This is King's ID. This is Paul's ID.
This is Jeff ID. This is Gautam ID.
This is Mamatha ID.
Like that you can see all these people.
And here status of this one.
Baseline means baseline means it's
already in production.
Already moved now,
implemented in production.
This is currently in Devu,
so it is still in the development phase.
Here you can see the Fraser.
This means development completed and
ready to implement.
So I will show I will tell the stages as
well.
Whenever you got the access for mainframe,
I will tell the stages also.
Yes.
So.
And in order to know,
I mean that particular TSID belongs to
who,
we just use TSO who is and then the ID
Yes, TSO. Suppose if I want to know TSO,
who is Carl?
right here. Okay.
I don't know the ID, but I know the name.
Ohh, the...
If I give TSO who is Carl?
Then you can see the with the Carl name,
how many people are there,
all the all those their IDs under their
names.
Okay, got it.
And also, Anatha,
the tags that you mentioned, CJ,
is there something you have done from
your side?
Oh.
The tags which you have mentioned, right,
CJ for platinum, you have given PLA,
so that that we have done it manually,
or is that already there in the previous?
Sorry, I am not able to, I mean,
get what you are asking.
The voice is not clear for me.
Can you go back to the previous?
Can you go to the previous screen? Yeah,
this one, this one, the tags, right?
This I gave, this one, yeah, manual,
I mean, I gave, oh,
CJ for change man, PLAT for platinum. You,
you, yeah.
for my convention I gave here.
Suppose if I not given this one,
Okay.
if I go here, yep,
every time if I want to access the change
management, yep,
then you have to come in here.
Then you have to give, yes.
Okay. Okay.
Then it will come here,
so instead of that, if I give CJ.
Gautam.
Then go back from here, FCHG,
directly it goes to here.
Okay, okay, got it.
Similarly, I get a part of five manager,
I give the FA.
If I not given this name,
every time I have to come here,
I have to select this tool.
Yeah, yeah.
No, yeah,
FA directory goes to the 5 million.
Yeah, yeah.
Similarly, FI means file manager.
This is the file manager.
To view the data sets under.
Yes.
Yeah, this is to filter. If we have to,
if we need to filter, you can.
The file is.
The file opens in the record format,
record layout format.
Mhm.
This is a PS file, suppose GDG.
If I open directly browser view mode,
I don't know the columns. I mean,
which column comes under which value?
Now, with this record format,
I opened it in File Manager.
Suppose the file is like this,
but here the 78 values belongs to which
which column,
what is the meaning for this 78 that I
don't know.
So if I open the file in the record
format, here we can say, OK, 78 is the.
Where is ID, then the next column is...
So, DC type.
So...
So I have a question here, Anatha.
So I know how to find this.
So we need to see the JCK where this
particular PS is being used,
by which program,
then we go to the copy book and we find
the copy book and then we give it here.
What is there any way other than that you
guys are doing to get the copy book?
yeah normally we yeah normally that is
the procedure but here the naming
convention the file name itself I have
the copy book name this is RC 569 is
there right this is the copy book so this
is the copy book library and I use it
Okay.
Mhm.
that copy book name here
And that is smart.
I am editing.
I'm editing this file with this copy book.
In that format, in this format.
Mmh.
Here one more thing is,
suppose if I want to open any folder,
suppose if I want to see that copy book,
then I have to go to 3.4,
then open that PDF,
then browse that copy book.
Instead of that, here there is a command,
we have to set up this one.
LB, CPY, RC569.
I want to see this copy book.
Instead of going 3.4, open that one,
I want to see this layout directly.
I can see here. This is the copy book.
Inside, we can see the warehouse ID.
Mmh.
Type Vero's number, Vero's name.
What is LB?
I don't know the abbreviation.
Once you get the access,
Okay, fine, fine.
you have to set up.
Can you show how to set it up?
Yeah.
Here, if you give the LB directly,
it goes to here.
Then you have to give the names,
the short form for this library.
Suppose this is a JCK library.
I gave the name as a JCK.
Ohh.
Under SRC, I gave the SRC.
This is a Cobol library.
Mmh.
And this is a copy book.
I just I opened right?
It will be CPY then RC5669, right?
So in this one I gave this is a copy book
Ohh.
library.
I set up this copy book library with the
name CPY.
That's why LB is the command,
CPY is the my short form of this library.
I'm opening this library to check this
member in this library.
You understand, right?
Can you scroll down?
Is there anything else?
Suppose.
No, how many you want?
You can frequently you access some
Okay, okay.
libraries, right?
Every time you have to go to open that
Huh.
one and browse that one. Instead of that,
which, yeah, this is a shortcut.
This is a shortcut.
Whichever I want to frequently access the
data sets.
I am giving the short form of that.
Suppose here I'm giving LB SRC.
I gave the copper copper cobal,
I gave the SRC source photo and.
The problem has been.
I believe some Rex is written in the
background, which is doing all this.
525.
Yeah, yeah, yes, yes, I'm opening this.
Yeah.
I'm opening this program.
Mhm.
They have opened.
And this is a program in this library.
My SRC, I gave the LBSRC, right?
This is the SRC.
For this library,
I set up the short form SRC for me.
Ohh.
If I give COB here.
Then.
LBSRC.
Double Ms. B 0525.
If I give you like this, it won't open.
Because SRC is not existing.
Mhm.
Yeah, that is on the right tag, okay?
Yeah. Now, if I want to open this one,
because I changed the from SRC to COB,
right? So, SRC COB.
0525 and it will open
Okay.
Nice.
To set up this one again,
you have to come here as LB,
then you can set up these libraries.
Oprah.
And, yep, coming to you, yeah,
change when we can frequently access this
tool, and...
DB2 Platinum is there,
but we have very limited access.
We never use this one.
You, but you use that URL,
whatever you shared with me, right?
That one.
Yes, yes.
Okay, most of the time you use that.
That is very convenient. Yeah. I mean,
the only engineering team cost team
access the tables through mainframe
because they, I mean,
frequently they have the 30 years of
experience in this environment, right? So
They use it mostly every time a QMF,
but offshore people use the query tool.
Suppose there is a complex query which I
have written select query very long.
So does that URL,
whatever you have provided, it works?
Yes, yes, it, yes, it works.
Any select statement we can execute
through query tool, but updates, inserts,
Oh.
deletes,
that we can't perform through query tool.
Only select statements work.
How do you write an update?
Under.
Foot.
If you want to do the update,
then you have to come to the mainframe,
then you have to write a query in QMF.
Okay,
you do it via QMF or you do it via the
SNTILA job.
Oh, is it?
Sometimes I use the KR,
but most of the times we use the job.
Okay. Can you show what? Yeah.
I will show, yeah, I will show, but, well,
once that part comes, I will show that.
OK, and one more thing, Anatha,
before we miss,
can you show how to suppose there is a
program I want to download it and see
that in Notepad,
because I may be comfortable in that,
so please show that part now to FTP also.
Okay, so...
Yeah, that is a FTP. Here,
here there is a tool is there, right?
Uh huh.
If you press tool,
reflect secure FTP is there.
Ohh.
You have to select that one.
Then it will open here.
Here you have to set up.
You have to set up the user ID,
mainframe user ID,
and this is my mainframe user ID and
password.
Mhm.
And JS to CAO.
This one you have to select you have to
give this name and here a user ID and
this is the password main frame user ID
and then main frame password.
Yeah.
Tosten.
Okay.
Whenever I mean there is a change in the
mainframe password,
every time you have to come in here and
you have to change it.
to connect to FTP.
So, once you set up that one,
this line will come, then do the connect.
It is like a just like a file.
Yeah, I know, I know. I just wanted to,
because it varies from client to client,
right? Just wanted to know how, yeah.
Yeah, now this is my mainframe.
This is my local mission.
Okay.
Is drag and drop?
These are all my PDSs, PDS.
Okay.
My user ID dot jet dot CPID.
My user ID dot jet dot Copy. Here I can.
OK.
I will show you.
Mmh.
This is the normal standard you follow
for creating personal PDS, right?
You will edit or Z dot anything.
That's what is followed, correct?
Ohh.
Ohh yeah,
engineering team following this one,
we are we are also doing the same,
but it is not necessary to create with
Yeah, that's fine.
the JED itself.
We can create with with any name.
Okay, okay. Yeah, this way it's funny.
I mean, it's easy to remember, right? So,
yeah.
Yeah, correct.
They are following this one,
so we are also following the same.
Okay.
So, Devu, you can see here, Devu.
So this is my mainframe and this is my
local mission.
These are all my EPS files, sir.
I can drag and drop directly from here to
here, here to here.
Okay.
That that is one way.
Second way is suppose if I want to
download in that TXT file.
Download as.
dot text.
dot Axay or whatever the name, if I want,
I can change it, then OK.
Here we have to set up the as thing.
Normally, it copies, like, on call events.
Do we need to keep option 6 open while we
are doing all this? That could be...
No, no, no, not required.
Okay.
Okay, this is a PDS.
Ohh.
Of TEST.
Normally it will close.
Yeah, Anatha,
I don't want to do this live.
Maybe you can try this later and show it
to us. I don't want to restore time here.
Okay.
OK.
Okay, so that way we can in the tools,
reflective FTP is there.
From here you can now download any source
code.
Okay.
Yeah, you know, school.
S colon SD.
You can see currently I am I opened the
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
two sessions.
So one is a SIS B and another one is a
system. Currently I'm in SIS B,
but my SIS B session is also running.
Suppose if I want to switch Windows key
shift F12.
This is my system.
Here again, I can see, yeah,
you can see everything same,
whatever setup I did in a system,
this analysis same setup,
but here we can't access the changement.
Changeman is not implemented in CN.
The remaining fault and laser,
all the tools we can access it except
Changeman.
Now I'm closing this one.
I closed that session. Now,
here it is appearing only.
Now you can see only speech active.
Okay.
Can you, can you show a,
can you go to your any of your test JCK
folder? How do you submit a SQL job?
I just wanted to see that also.
Want to submit or just to you?
No, no, no, you don't have to submit.
Just go there.
I just wanted to see the structure of the
JCK.
I mean,
the control cards and all those things.
Yeah, how you are writing the queries,
right?
Hmm.
We want to see how the queries we are
writing.
Yeah,
just show me a sample that is enough.
See.
Just scroll down.
OK, Jeff to 01 and this is the libraries.
This is for prod, I believe, right?
Yeah, this is for.
Annie Prod.
No, EU product. Here, if you see DB2E,
right, E means Europe.
Huh.
Then P means problem. I mean, for the US,
not Europe. Similarly, DB2E for Europe,
people.
Non-Europa.
Okay.
And what about TEST?
Now, this is a test, DB to T.
Yeah, yeah.
I think test only one is there, right?
For Europe and North America, it's same.
Yes.
For Europe, there is no test environment.
It is a QA environment.
So is this DB2Q?
Not a DB2Q, I will show DSM,
that we call DSM.
Where we can see that one, I will show.
If you go,
Okay.
Yeah.
But we have to go there.
Yeah, that that end, right?
Ian.
Yeah.
You know.
5 minutes and DB2 is there.
File manager, DBT is there, so FMDB.
Inside.
Okay, not here also.
Here you can see.
Ah, okay, okay, okay. Bye, bye.
You understand, right?
TP is for you, you should be T.
Normally, with...
Yeah.
Production.
DB to P production means it is a
non-Europe one.
DB to T it is a test environment.
DB to G is a production Europe one.
Ohh.
Deepthi to Q, it is not active.
Okay.
I mean, I never seen this is active. We,
I mean, nobody used this one.
Mhm.
And DSN is a QA environment for Europe.
Okay.
And DB2, yes, is the QA environment,
QA database. It says for non-Europe.
Okay.
Yeah, I wanted to remember all those.
Once you started using the easy,
you can get it similar, same,
These are great.
Yeah, yeah.
same we can see here.
Yeah, I was about to say that query tool,
right? The query tool, right? Drop down.
We never.
Yes, yes, drop down, we can see it,
same thing we can see here, Devu to.
Yeah, yeah.
Datta.
URP is a Europe production.
DB2 broad means non-Europe production.
DB2 sure means it is a non-Europe QA
environment.
DB2 demo is the Europe QA environment and
DB2.
Test is the test environment for the
non-Europa.
These are the five environments.
Yeah.
Same here,
also five environments are there.
So, in the JCK,
we just need to change that part,
the JCK which you showed, and that's it,
right?
Yes.
Yes. Yeah.
Suppose if we want to find update
Okay.
something,
delete something in suppose non-Europe
queue environment,
you have to give it to yes there.
Okay.
Suppose Europe to environment DSN.
Okay.
Here, you have to give,
you have to change that DSL.
Like that.
Here also DSN, here also DSN. And here,
this is the option.
Iyer call fare is optional.
Even if you are not giving this one.
You can execute like this.
can execute like this.
So it directly this table refers the DSN.
DSN means it is a Devu to Europe queue
environment.
But for safe, we gave, I mean,
sometimes we use Iyer call for also.
So, we need to change line 10, 14, and 16.
Yes.
Fourteen and 16,
the libraries DB to DSN system and the
library, and here also this library,
these three only we have to change.
Okay.
Based on your, I mean,
which database you want to access,
these three has to change.
Remaining query,
whatever you can write here.
Mhm.
At the end,
this is a compulsory we have to give
without this one.
If you are not giving a single semi colon,
this query won't execute.
Ohh,
we need to give so many semicolons that
Not semicolor, minimum one.
is mandatory is in.
Okay,
I thought I thought we need to give that
one in this one.
No, no, no, no, actually,
if you give like this,
Okay, okay.
suppose if you go like this,
it will give the error,
it won't execute this one minimum,
minimum one is required.
I know,
I know that is needed as per syntax.
Suppose if you want to write multiple
statements.
You have to write like this.
Yeah, that is like the scope terminator.
The end one, yeah, scoping the end one,
either a single or multiple.
Multiple means,
suppose if you give the multiple here,
Understood.
this one won't execute.
Got it.
If you have multiple statements,
only one semi colon scope terminator,
we have to give.
If you are getting multiple,
then the rest won't execute.
So.
Then, coming to...
Yeah?
What frequently we use Changeman and File
Manager, File Aid, and File Manager DB2.
These four only, here we use it.
The remaining options are there,
but we not under IOAs also, we use it.
But operational point of view, we go here.
For a developer point of view,
maybe not required.
But I will cover this IOA. What is IOA?
That also I will cover it.
What are the active jobs are there?
Suppose there are 10 jobs running one by
Okay.
one.
So which is currently active in Control M,
in Control M,
whatever we are seeing Control M,
the same we can see here also in
mainframe.
Control them is outside, right?
So same thing we can see in mainframe
with IOA.
Is nothing but a scheduler.
We we want to use this one frequently,
because every time we use the Control M.
And the rest,
there are so many tools are there,
but we never used all these.
Whenever we have the time,
you can explore it.
So whatever you showed now, Anatha,
you are going to go through each and
every of them and give us a KT, right?
Yes, this is just a high-level,
high-level one.
Mmh.
I'm just showing these are the tools are
there, but once you get the access,
I'll go inside and I will show you how to
create it, how to use it, use that tool.
Is that fine, or?
Once you get the access,
you won't require me,
Ah.
you yourself explore everything that I
know, but I will give from my side,
Yeah, so...
I will give it.
Sid, how do you want to take it? For me,
like without access also,
I am ready to go.
So that once we get the access,
If you have the access,
you can practice it. You can practice it.
we'll start exploring.
Yeah.
Once you get the access,
immediately you can practice it.
I'm fine. Debasish anyway,
even if you get now,
Yeah.
we can still refer the recording and go
ahead once we get there.
Yeah, correct.
I am also fine now.
Yeah.
So, even I'm okay with if, if you go,
if you go ahead with the KT now,
once we get...
Those things by our own,
and obviously you are there,
you are not leaving, right? So,
we'll ask you, we'll not let you leave,
even if you want to.
Yeah, normally you know, right? 3.3, 3.4,
3.13 comparison. All these are common.
Yeah,
this is an Alluri know I wanted to show.
Yeah, I know I told PRD.
Just 3.3.13 - can you go once?
Two.13 is the comparison, so for three.
Comparison, yeah, yeah, yeah,
we had many in rider, it's just 3.13,
right?
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Same there, and so same.
Okay.
It is 3.13. OK.
And I hear your user ID,
you are currently in which system you are
there.
This is a point.
Have a second number.
And this is the release as pay for.
A version.
time that we can see here. Yeah,
fault analyzer, Devu,
I not shown that part,
where we can see here.
Here, E.
Then, three.
Once you come over here, this is a PMF,
here Q. Before going to here,
which system you want to access,
that you have to tell it here.
I want to see DB to T.
Then it will open this one when I have to.
F2U, and you hit now, right?
You have two.
F2OK.
And then what do you enter here?
Under the name of the objects, PC, Yasin,
001.
That's our table name, right?
Yeah, this is the table name.
Okay.
I need to come here, actually.
To list F6F6.
Don.
Is it case sensitive?
No.
Then once you query is ready,
then you can press F2.
You can see.
To come out just F3.
Yes, sir.
Just like a select, we can run update,
insert, delete also, right?
Yes, definitely.
And hit on run. That's all.
Yes, yes, yes.
But, yeah,
but better to use this rather than a job.
Um...
In case we need to do something,
because this will be faster, right?
Yeah, yes, yes.
Similarly, suppose this is a queue.
Suppose if I want to go through spoofy,
then
B. Circle One.
Normally, you know, right?
You can go here,
you can write that code and execute it.
semi colon multiple times hit enter F3.
Yes.
and to execute the Devu commands you have
to go Devu command 7.
These are all normal common things
everywhere for any main environment it is
the same.
How do we,
how do you know the cost of a particular
query? Cost in the sense I like.
If you go KMF, when query is executing,
it will show, let's say top corner,
the cost.
Okay.
But for spoofy, it won't show.
If it is a bulk,
I think it was spoofy also will show
estimated time and cost.
Here, IMS options are there,
but we never went inside because whenever
there is a, I mean,
any changes required in the Ms.
always Jeff only taken to place.
Even the Kim, uh, and there is a, ohh,
will not work on the IMS.
Oh.
How do we get to see all the tables and
the indexes on all the objects,
DB2 objects?
Ryan.
I know, via select, we can, via CSI BM,
we can do that,
If you go.
but is there any other way?
If you go here, 3.4 and Copy DSV,
one library is there, yeah, are there,
The ACL.
Tecljen.
right?
Ohh.
We go here.
TC.
I mean, here you can see.
How about the indexes?
Indexes we can't see here.
I mean, in mainstream environment,
we can't see the, I mean,
we won't see the indexes. If we want,
I mean, there is no DDL library here.
So only in the DDL library is there,
then we can see what are the indexes for
this one.
Ohh, there only who can refer,
so always you have to refer to C.C.
Mhm.
indexes.
Okay, who is the DBA here?
Ohh.
Clark Miller is the senior most guy.
Okay.
BBA.
This guy.
Clark Miller, okay, got it.
Mhm.
Is the most database DBA.
I think this gets so more 30 to 40 years
in the system.
Usually, that's how they will work.
Yeah.
One more thing,
suppose if I don't want to come to here,
I want to see how many tables are there.
Then LV, CPY, PC, start.
Mmh.
You can see 1323 tables are there.
And how to know which and which ones are
active, which ones are not active?
There is, is there any way?
No.
Good.
There is a, I mean,
there is a mechanism with tools.
Platinum tools is the right.
Mmh.
It is this platinum tool.
We can see,
but we don't have the permissions.
Many,
whatever engineering team and DBA team,
Mm.
whatever, they have the permissions,
we don't have it.
Engineering team is Carl's team, right?
Yes, yes.
Okay, okay.
So, you showed today?
They have the file manager for the file
manager for the IMS also. IMS databases,
Yeah.
IMS DB, they have the file manager.
But.
But you, you don't access.
So, from last and the starting,
I never get the chance to check on this
one.
Okay,
good that we don't have to deal with IMS
Because it, no, actually,
they don't have it, they namesake,
here.
it has the IMS, but inside everything,
maybe to maybe to only.
Oh.
Even by seeing the program IMS database,
they open the DB2 table only. If you,
I mean,
if you want to see that data in IMS,
they always refer the DB2 table only.
Okay, both get synced up in some manner,
some process is doing that. I am missing.
Very, very little,
very little IMS databases are there,
but some some economies is there to sync
up the data.
Okay.
That, that we don't know.
Mmh.
So, today we covered Platinum 3.4, 3.13.
Yeah.
Right, sorry,
not letting them queue my bad,
letting them you cannot access, right?
Yeah.
What are you up for changing management
or DB2 and what are the regions in DB2 we
have written? These, I mean,
whatever the extensions,
what are the tools we have in mainframe?
Yes, I covered,
I gave the just overview and I went
inside, yes, I gave the overview.
Oh.
Tomorrow,
I will continue with the tables very
early. Tomorrow,
I will continue the naming conventions,
the file naming conventions,
how it is in the mainframe, suppose.
mainframe, PS files, how production files,
how it starts,
what is the job naming conventions,
that part I will cover it tomorrow.
Okay.
program name, first three letters,
what it refers, the next character,
what it refers, that I will cover it.
Bye.
And.
So, in detail, like change man,
file manager, file data,
and all those things will go later.
That's what you said. OK.
Yes, sir.
I mean, in detail,
will go once you get the access,
Yeah.
I will show how to create it and one or
two packages while you are creating,
I will guide it.
Okay.
So tomorrow should I send the invite same
time? Same set of invites?
You not,
you not set up the invite for the next
one week.
No, I did not do that.
I thought you sent, you put,
you create an invite till the 16th.
I, I...
Till 16th, right? No, no,
I did not get that instruction from you
Yeah.
or assurance. That's the reason I did not.
I just raised it for today. I'll do it.
I'll set up a recurring meeting till 16th.
Same set of invites.
I will say till 16, yeah, till 16,
how much I can cover. If required,
I will extend if it is sufficient,
then from 19 onwards,
so maybe he will take the MDO MDO Project.
Details: M.D.O. means mark down,
mark down optimizations.
I think I don't know the full form,
but Gautam worked a lot on M.D.O. project.
Currently, I mean,
you are part of the KFL conversion and
Okay.
MDO. So, MDO is this guy, Lucas and Carl.
Him and KFL, only Carl.
Carl handles that project.
Okay.
Mmh.
So, MDO, MDO, you work in,
so maybe he covered it later.
We'll see.
First I will cover the main frame
Okay.
environment and other tools and Foot
Locker technology. What is the SKU?
What is the case slot? What is the item?
What is the bricks and mortars?
You?
I mean, there is a 12 digit item number.
If I,
if you break down what is the division
department,
what is what they are calling the KPL FTL
is the right? What is the FTL?
What is KPL?
What is that the the technology put
Locker?
Oh, technology, I will cover it then.
Okay, okay, got it.
Okay.
Yeah, thank you. Thank you so much,
Anatha.
You can stop the recording.
Yeah.